Marco Damonte

mdtux89.github.io

CONTACT Information 26 Canaan Lane EH104SY Edinburgh (UK) $+44\ 7435654361$ m.damonte@sms.ed.ac.uk

Summary

I'm currently pursuing a PhD degree at the University of Edinburgh, UK. My research focuses on Natural Language Processing, the field of Artifical Intelligence that deals with natural languages. In particular, Im working on software algorithms to extract the underlying meaning of sentences (Natural Language Understanding) and generating new sentences given the intended meaning (Natural Language Generation). For this purpose, I am studying a meaning representation framework called Abstract Meaning Representation (AMR).

EDUCATION

University of Edinburgh

Old College, South Bridge, Edinburgh EH8 9YL, United Kingdom

PhD in Natural Language Processing

01/09/2015 -

Supervised by Shay Cohen

Teaching assistant for Natural Language Understanding (2018), Topics in NLP (2017), Advanced NLP (2016/2017), Informatics 2A (2015)

Member of the Edina team at the Amazon Alexa Prize 2016/2017

Instituto Superior Técnico, Portugal

Av. Rovisco Pais 1, 1049-001 Lisboa, Portugal

Lisbon Machine Learning School

21/07/2016 - 28/07/2016

University of Edinburgh

Old College, South Bridge, Edinburgh EH8 9YL, United Kingdom

Artificial Intelligence MSc - Distinction

08/09/2014 - 31/08/2015

Dissertation: "Machine Translation with Coarse Lexical Semantics"

Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Norway

Hogskoleringen 1, 7491 Trondheim, Norway

Erasmus exchange program

05/01/2012 - 14/06/2012

Courses: Compilers, Web Intelligence, Natural Language Interfaces, Requirements and Testing.

University of Genoa, Italy

Via Balbi, 5, 16126 Genova GE, Italy

BSc and MSc in Information Engineering (107/110)

09/2008 - 06/2014

Dissertation: "COOPERA: a Cost-effective Open-source Platform for Empirical AI and Robotics"

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Amazon Lab126

1100 Enterprise Way, Sunnyvale, California, United States

Applied Scientist Intern

11/06/2018 - 14/09/2018

Machine Learning for Natural Language Understanding and Conversational Agents

Facebook, London

10 Brock Street, London NW1 3FG, United Kingdom

Software Engineer Intern

25/06/2017 - 16/9/2017

Machine Learning for Ads Ranking

University of Genoa, Italy Via Balbi, 5, 16126 Genova GE, Italy

Research Collaborator

06/06/2014 - 05/09/2014

Reinforcement Learning applied to Robotics

Publications

- [1] Marco Damonte and Shay B Cohen. Cross-lingual abstract meaning representation parsing. To appear at NAACL, 2018.
- [2] Marco Damonte and Shay B Cohen. Structural neural encoders for AMR-to-text generation. In Proceedings of NAACL, 2019.
- [3] Marco Damonte, Shay B Cohen, and Giorgio Satta. An incremental parser for abstract meaning representation. Proceedings of EACL, 2017.
- [4] Marco Damonte, Rahul Goel, and Tagyoung Chung. Practical semantic parsing for spoken language understanding. In *Proceedings of NAACL*, 2019.
- [5] Fuad Issa, Marco Damonte, Shay B. Cohen, Xiaohui Yan, and Yi Chang. Abstract meaning representation for paraphrase detection. In To appear at NAACL, 2018.
- [6] Ben Krause, Marco Damonte, Mihai Dobre, Daniel Duma, Joachim Fainberg, Federico Fancellu, Emmanuel Kahembwe, Jianpeng Cheng, and Bonnie Webber. Edina: Building an open domain socialbot with self-dialogues. arXiv preprint arXiv:1709.09816, 2017.
- [7] Renars Liepins, Ulrich Germann, Guntis Barzdins, Alexandra Birch, Steve Renals, Susanne Weber, Peggy van der Kreeft, Herve Bourlard, João Prieto, Ondrej Klejch, et al. The summa platform prototype. In Proceedings of EACL, 2017.

SCHOLARSHIPS

UK/EU Master's Scolarship for the academic session 2014/2015 (University of Edinburgh)

Sponsored participation to Amazon Alexa Prize 2016/2017

PhD research supported by a grant from Bloomberg and by the H2020 project SUMMA

Peer reviewing NAACL 2018

ACL 2018

3rd Workshop on Representation Learning for NLP (RepL4NLP 2018)

ACL 2019

4rd Workshop on Representation Learning for NLP (RepL4NLP 2019)

EMNLP-IJCNLP 2019

Tools

Toolkits: PyTorch, Torch, OpenNMT, CoreNLP, Spacy, Moses, HTK, Festival, NLTK, Wordnet.

Programming languages: Python, Java, C++, C, Clojure, PHP, JavaScript, Matlab, R.